We were wondering what was taking so long...
我们还说你拿礼物这么半天还不回来
...but now we understand. You were doing this.
现在才知道你在干这个
Okay. I wanted to surprise you, but....
我本想给你们个惊喜的
For your housewarming gift,
作为乔迁礼
I got you a baby chick and a baby duck.
送给你们一只小鸡一只小鸭
Really? You got us a chick and a duck?
真的  给我们小鸡小鸭
Oh, great.
太好了
Just what you want for
家里有婴儿
a new house with infants. Bird feces!
鸟粪真是锦上添花啊
But they must've jumped off the table.
一定是从桌子上跳下去了
Now they're gone!
现在都不见了啊
Don't worry, we'll find them.
别着急  慢慢找
Actually, I'm gonna go check on the twins.
我去看孩子去了
Oh, God! What did I just step on?
天呐  我刚才踩着什么了
It's okay. It's just an egg roll.
没事了  就是个蛋卷
You stepped on my egg roll?!
你竟敢踩我的蛋卷
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I didn't know to look for Chinese food on the floor.
谁会想到地上会有中国菜
Just put it on a plate and leave.
放到盘子里  然后快走
- Okay. Let's find these birds. - All right.
-好了  开始找吧  -好
Wait, wait. You hear that?
等等  听到了没
They're in the table!
在桌子里
Well, that can't be good.
这可不妙了
- We gotta get them out of there! - How?
-必须要取出来  -怎么取
Maybe we can lure them out. You know any birdcalls?
也许能引诱他们出来  你知道鸟怎么叫吗
Oh, tons. I'm quite the woodsman.
当然了  我就是干伐木工的
Well, maybe we can just tip the table a little.
把桌子一头抬起来点也许管用
Joey, wait! The ball!
乔伊等一下  球
So, what do we do?
现在怎么办
Maybe we can open this up somehow.
不清楚  也许边上什么地方能打开吧
Okay.
好
No. It's all glued together.
不行啊  都粘上了
Does that mean we have to bust it open?
也就是说要生撬开
- I don't know. Maybe. - Oh, my God.
-不知道也许吧  -天呐
I know. It's-- It's the foosball table.
我明白  这可是足球桌啊
All right, you know what? We don't have a choice.
没有办法了
It's like I would have said in that sci-fi movie
就像我在一部科幻电影里面的台词一样
if I'd have gotten the part.
如果我当初赢到角色的话
Those are our men in there, and we have to get them out...
"里面是我们的人  必须要救出来"
...even if I have to sacrifice the most important thing in my life...
"即使要牺牲我生命中最重要的东西...
...my time machine.
我的时间机器"
- Did that movie ever get made? - It did not.
-这电影拍出来了没   -根本也没拍
Ross, where are you going?
罗斯  你去哪里
To talk to Rachel.
去找瑞秋啊
Isn't that why we took a ride in the death cab?
所以我才坐死亡计程车来的
You're walking up to her at the gate?
你就直接去登机口
Have you never chased anyone through the airport before?
以前在没在机场追过人
Not since my cop show got canceled.
我的警察戏镜头被取消之后就没有过了
You have to get a ticket to get past security.
必须先买票才能通过安检
What? We're never gonna make it.
那就赶不及了啊
Not with that attitude. Now, haul ass!
这种态度肯定不行  快滚过来
Okay, if you could all walk slower,
大家再走慢点
that'd be great.
就好了
- Madame, your passport, please. - Oh, my God.
-女士  看一下您的护照   -天呐
I was afraid I wouldn't remember my high school French.
我还害怕高中学的法语都忘干净了呢
But I understood every word you just said.
你刚才说的每个字我都听明白了
- Your boarding pass, please. - Oh, sure.
-看一下您的登机牌  -哦  当然
Shoot, I had it. Oh, I can't believe this.
讨厌  我有的  真不敢相信
Madame, if you don't have your--
女士  如果您没有...
I have it, I have it!
我有我有我有我有
Okay, I can't find it,
哎呀  找不到
but I remember that I was in seat 32C...
不过我清楚记得 我的座位号是32C
...because that's my bra size.
因为我罩杯号就是这个
Madame. You must have your boarding pass--
女士  您必须要有登机牌  否则……
Ok, fine. But you know what?
好吧
If I was in 36D, we would not be having this problem.
我要是36D  就没这么多麻烦了
- Hi. I need a ticket. - Just one?
-您好  我要买一张票  -就买一张
I drive you here,
我开车这么大老远送你过来
and I don't get to see how it works out?
不能看看结局啥样
Fine. Two tickets. I need two tickets.
好吧  两张  我买两张票
We're on our honeymoon.
我们在度蜜月呢
And the destination?
目的地是
I don't care. Whatever's the cheapest.
随便  最便宜的吧
I'm so lucky I married you.
我嫁给你真是太走运了哈
Oh, shoot. Damn it. Where is it?
啊  靠  妈的  哪里去了
I found it. I found it. I told you I would find it.
啊  找到了找到了  哈   找到了  早和你说了我有
In your face. You're a different person.
你不是那个人了
Sorry.
抱歉
Okay. Flight 421, Paris.
421航班  巴黎
I don't see it. Do you see it?
找不到  你呢
No. Did we miss it?
我也找不着  错过了
No, no, it's impossible. It doesn't leave for another 20 minutes.
不可能  20分钟后才起飞的
Maybe we have the flight number wrong.
航班号错了吧
God.
天
- Hello. - Hey, it's me. Here's Ross.
-嗨  -嗨  是我  给你罗斯
What?
什么
Hey. Hey, listen--
嗨  听着...
You wouldn't believe the cute noises the twins are making.
天啊  俩孩子的声音太可爱了
Wait, listen.
罗斯你听
But Monica--
但是莫妮卡
Monica...
莫妮卡...
I'm sorry. They were doing it before.
抱歉  他俩刚才还出声来着啊
That's all right. Listen, listen.
好  听着...
Oh, wait, wait. Here they go again.
等等  又来了
Monica...
莫妮卡...
- Monica? - Isn't that cute?
-莫妮卡   -可爱吧
That is precious! Listen....
可爱死了  听着
I need Rachel's flight information.
我要瑞秋的航班信息
Oh, okay.
哦  好
All right, it's flight 421. Leaves at 8:40.
421航班  8点40起飞
Yes, that's what I had . It's not on the board.
是啊  就是这个  看板上找不到
That's what it says here.
这里就是这样写的啊
Flight 421. Leaves at 8:40. Newark Airport.
421航班  8点40起飞  纽瓦克机场
- What? - Newark Airport.
-什么  -纽瓦克机场
Why? Where are you?
怎么了  你们在哪里
JFK.
肯尼迪机场
Don't worry, you guys!
别着急
We're gonna get you out of there!
会把你们救出来的
And we're also gonna buy you tiny bird hearing aids.
然后再给你们买小鸟用助听器
Okay. Here goes.
好  来了
What's the matter?
怎么了
I need to say goodbye to the table first.
我要先跟桌子告别
I understand.
我理解
Okay.
好
Table...
桌子
...you have given us so many great times.
你曾经给予我们太多的欢乐时光
And you guys, Jordan, Victor, Joel....
你们大伙  乔丹  维克多  还有约耳
All of you guys. What can I say?
你们所有人  我得说
You guys make us look good.
是你们让我俩更有形象
- You want to say anything? - I don't know.
-你想说什么  -不知道
Except that, for one last time....
不过  最后一次
Good game...
干得好...
Good game.
干得好
Okay. Here we go.
好吧  来  动手
I can't do it.
我下不了手
Well, I can't do it either.
我也下不了手啊
Hey. Did you find them?
找到没
Yeah. They're stuck inside the table.
在桌子里面呢
And we have to bust it open, but neither of us can do it.
必须要撬开  不过我们俩都下不去手
Oh, well, sure. It's got to be so hard.
是啊  太难了
I'll do it. Give me.
我来吧  给我
Phoebe!
菲比
No, no, no!
不要啊
Wow, I've never gone this fast before.
以前从没开这么快过
Phoebe, forget it, okay?
菲比  算了吧
Newark is, like, an hour away.
纽瓦克  一个小时才能到
There's no way we'll make it in time.
根本赶不上
She's got her cell. You could call her.
她拿着手机呢  打电话
I am not doing this over the phone.
我不要在电话上谈
You don't have any other choice.
你没其他办法了啊
- Hello? - Rachel. Oh, good.
-喂  -瑞秋  太好了
By the way, did you just get on the plane?
对了  你是不是刚上飞机
- Yeah. - For what is worse, we would have caught her...
-是啊 -不管怎样提一句   如果机场没去错
...if we were at the right airport.
我们已经追上她了
- Rachel, hang on. - No. No. No.
-瑞  等着  -不不不
Phoebe, is everything okay?
菲比  你那边不要紧吧
Actually, no. No. You have to get off the plane.
事实上  有点事情  你必须下飞机
- What? Why? - I have this feeling that...
-啊  为什么  -我有种感觉
...something's wrong with it.
飞机有问题
Something is wrong with the left phalange.
左"弗兰基"有毛病
Oh, honey, I'm sure there's nothing wrong with the plane.
亲爱的  飞机肯定没问题的
Look, I have to go.
马上要起飞了
I love you, and l will call you the minute I get to Paris.
我爱你  一到巴黎就打电话
What was that?
你刚才说什么
Oh, that was just my crazy friend.
哦  我的疯朋友
She told me to get off the plane
让我下飞机
because she had a "feeling" that there...
因为她就是感觉到
...was something wrong with the left phalange.
飞机左"弗兰基"有毛病
Okay. That doesn't sound good.
听起来可不妙吧
Oh, I wouldn't worry about it.
不用担心
She comes up with this stuff,
她老是这样
and she's almost never right.
而且几乎从没对过
But she is sometimes.
也就是说她也有对的时候
Well....
啊
What are you doing?
你要干吗
I can't take this plane now.
这飞机我不能坐
Excuse me, sir. Where are you going?
对不起先生  您去哪里
I have to get off this plane.
我要下飞机
Her friend has a feeling
她朋友感觉到
something's wrong with the left phalange.
飞机左"弗兰基"有毛病
Could I get some peanuts?
请给我拿点花生好吗
What's wrong with the plane?
飞机怎么了
There's nothing wrong.
飞机一点异常都没有
The left phalange.
左"弗兰基"有毛病了
There's no "phalange."
根本就没有什么"弗兰基"
Oh, my God. This plane doesn't even have a phalange.
天呐  这破飞机连"弗兰基"都没有
- I'm not flying on it. - Ma'am. Please sit down.
-我不飞了 -女士  请您坐好
What's going on?
出什么事情了
We're getting off. There is no phalange!
我们都下去  飞机上根本就没有"弗兰基"
This is ridiculous. I--
太荒谬了吧  我...
Yeah, okay.
啊随便吧
All right. My job here is done.
好了  工作完成
That was impressive.
你太强了
Yeah. You didn't even use the tools for most of it.
大部分连工具都没用就弄下来了
Yeah, they were just slowing me down.
啊  工具太碍事了
All right. I gotta get back to the babies.
好啦  我回去看孩子了
See you girls later.
你们俩个丫头一会儿见
- Sorry about the table, man. - Yeah.
-真抱歉阿  桌子这样了  -嗯
You gonna buy a new one?
要买新的吗
Probably not. No.
也许不会了
I don't know how much I'm gonna want to play
你走后我估计
after you go.
也不会怎么玩了
- At least we got these little guys out. - Yeah.
-至少这两个小家伙救出来了 -是啊
We were worried about you.
我们还担心你们呢
I guess I better get used to things
以后就多习惯有东西
crapping in my hand, huh?
在我手里拉屎吧
I'm gonna miss these little guys.
我会想你们的  小家伙
It was nice having birds around again.
再养养鸟还真挺不错的
Hey, you know what?
这样吧
Maybe we should keep them here with you.
它们就交给你了
What?
什么
Yeah. We got a lot going on right now.
嗯  我们现在也忙得要死
And plus, here, they'd have their own room.
而且这里也有它们的房间啊
I could get a goose!
还可以再养只鹅
You know, I think you're set with the poultry.
我觉得家禽类这两只就够了
Thanks, man. You hear that, you guys?
多谢了  听到没有
You're gonna get to stay here.
你们要留在这里啦
And it's good...
而且这样也挺好的
...you know, because....
因为
Because now you have a reason
你就有理由
to come visit.
多回来看看了
I think there may be another reason.
其实还有另外一个理由
So....
那么...
Awkward hug or lame cool-guy handshake?
尴尬的拥抱呢  还是假酷男握手呢
Yeah, well, you know,
啊  那好
lame cool-guy handshake.
还是假酷男握手吧
Ma'am, I assure you, the plane is fine.
女士  我想您保证  飞机没有问题
And you fixed the phalange?
"弗兰基"也修好啦
Yes. The phalange's fixed.
没错  修好了
As a matter of fact,
而且
we've put a whole lot of extra phalanges onboard,
还又带了许多备用的
just in case.
以防万一
- Where is she? - I don't see her.
-她在哪儿  -看不到
- Rachel! Rachel Green! - There she is!
-瑞秋  瑞秋·格林  -她在那里
Rachel! Rachel!
瑞秋  瑞秋
Whoa, do you have a boarding pass?
先生  您有登机牌吗
No. I just have to talk to someone.
没有  我就是要找里面的一个人说句话
I'm sorry. You need a boarding pass.
对不起  没有登机牌不能再往前走了
- No, no. But you don't-- - Rachel!
-不...  你不...  -瑞秋
What? Oh, my God.
怎么了  我的天啊
What are you guys doing here?
你们来这干嘛
Okay. You're on.
轮到你了
What? What, Ross?
怎么了  怎么了罗斯
Okay, you're scaring me. What's going on?
你吓到我了  出什么事了
- Okay. Thing is.... - Yeah.
-嗯  我想说的是...  -什么
- Don't go. - What?
-不要走  -什么
Please, please stay with me.
留下来和我在一起
I am so in love with you. Please don't go.
我太爱你了  求求你不要走
- Oh, my God. - I know. I know.
-天呐  -我知道  我知道
I shouldn't have waited till now to say it,
不应该拖到现在才说的
but-- That was stupid, okay? I'm sorry.
我太笨了  对不起
But I'm telling you now.
不过我现在和你说
I love you.
我爱你
Do not get on this plane.
不要上飞机
Miss, are you boarding the plane?
小姐  您是否要上飞机
Hey, hey.
嘿
I know you love me. I know you do.
我知道你爱我  我都知道
- Miss. - I....
-小姐  -我...
l.... I have to get on the plane.
我要上飞机
- No, you don't. - Yes, I do.
-不要  别上飞机  -我要上
- No, you don't. I do. - They're waiting for me, Ross.
-不要  别上飞机  -都等着我呢  罗斯
I can't do this right now,
我现在真的不能这么做
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
Rachel.
瑞秋
I'm so sorry.
真的对不起
I really thought she'd stay.
我本来以为她会留下的
I know.
我知道
I'm sorry.
我很遗憾
Well, that's it.
那么  就这样了
Everything's packed.
好了  收拾完毕
This is weird.
啊  感觉有点怪啊
I know.
我明白
Yeah.
嗯
Does this mean there's nothing to eat?
也就是说没吃的了
I put three lasagnas in your freezer.
我在你冰箱里面放了三盘意大利宽面条
I love you.
我爱你
Hey.
嗨
Hey. Did you guys make it in time?
怎样  赶上了吗
Yeah, yeah.
赶上了
He talked to her, but she got on the plane anyway.
他跟她说了 不过她最后还是上了飞机
Where's Ross?
罗斯呢
He went home. He didn't want to see anybody.
回家了  他谁也不想见
Ross. Hi, it's me.
"罗斯  嗨  是我"
I just got back on the plane,
"我刚回到飞机上"
and I just feel awful.
"我现在感觉太难受了"
That is so not how I wanted
"我绝不希望
things to end with us.
我们之间这么就完了"
It's just that I wasn't expecting
"只是我根本没料到
to see you.
你会出现"
And all of a sudden you're there
"猛一下子你就来了
and saying these things.
还说那些话"
Now I'm just sitting here
"我现在坐在这里
and thinking...
静静地想"
...of all the stuff I should have said
"想我应该说
and I didn't.
却没有说出口的话"
I mean, I didn't even get to tell you
"我甚至都没跟你说
that I love you too.
我也爱你"
Because of course I do. I love you.
"因为当然我是爱你的  我爱你"
I love you.
"我爱你"
What am I doing? I love you.
"我到底在干什么  我爱你  "
I've got to see you.
"我要见你
I've got to get off this plane.
我要下飞机"
Oh, my God.
天呐
Okay, excuse me.
"打扰一下"
Miss, please sit down.
"小姐  请坐下"
No, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry,
"真对不起
but I need to get off the plane.
我要立刻下飞机
I need to tell someone that I love them.
去告诉他我爱他"
Miss, I can't let you off.
"小姐  现在不能下飞机"
Let her off the plane!
让她下飞机
I am afraid you are gonna have to take a seat.
"请您务必坐好"
Oh, please, Miss. You don't understand.
"求求你了  你不明白  "
Try to understand!
试着理解啊
Come on, miss, isn't there any way
"小姐
that you can just let me off the--?
有没有办法让我能下..."
No! No!
不要
Oh, my God. Did she get off the plane?
我的天啊  到底下没下飞机
Did she get off the plane?
到底下没下飞机
I got off the plane.
我下飞机了
You got off the plane.
你下飞机了
I do love you.
我真的爱你
I love you too,
我也爱你
and I am never letting you go again.
再也不会让你走了
Okay. Because this is where I want to be.
我也希望留在这里
No more messing around.
再也不要浪费时间
I don't want to mess this up again.
我不想再搞砸了
Me neither. We're done being stupid.
我也不想  我们再也不要做蠢事了
Okay. It's you and me, all right? This is it.
只有你和我  好不好  只有你和我
This is it. Unless we're on a break.
就这样了  除非我们是在感情间歇期
Don't make jokes now.
现在就别开玩笑了
Okay, please be careful with that.
请小心点
It was my grandmother's. Be careful.
这是我祖母的  请务必小心
Thank you.
多谢
If that falls off the truck,
如果这玩意儿从卡车掉下去了
it wouldn't be the worst thing.
也没什么大不了的
I know.
是啊
Seems smaller somehow.
看起来好像小了一圈
Has it always been purple?
一直都是紫色的
Look around, you guys.
小家伙们  看看四周吧
This was your first home.
这里是你们第一个家
And it was a happy place,
一个幸福快乐的地方
filled with love and laughter.
充满了爱与欢笑
But more important,
更重要的是
because of rent control, it was a frigging steal.
租金管制简直就是明抢啊
Hey, do you realize that, at one time or another,
嗨  你们有没有意识到
we all lived in this apartment?
我们每个人都在这里住过
Oh, yeah. That's true.
还真是
I haven't.
我没有
What about that summer during college
你大学有一年暑假
that you lived with Grandma...
过来和祖母住
...and you tried to make it as a dancer?
然后你想靠跳舞来挣钱
Do you realize we almost made it 10 years
你有没有意识到
without that coming up?
这都十年前的骨灰了你还往出挖
Oh, honey, I forgot.
亲爱的  我差点忘了
I promised Treeger that we'd leave our keys.
我答应崔格把钥匙留下
Oh, okay.
好
- So I guess this is it. - Yeah.
-都结束了  -是啊
I guess so.
应该是吧
This is harder than I thought it would be.
比想象中的还要难啊
Oh, it's gonna be okay.
会好的
Come on.
好了
Do you guys have to go to the new house now,
你们俩是马上去新房子
or do you have some time?
能挤出点时间来吗
We got some time.
还有点时间
- Okay. Should we get some coffee? - Sure.
-去喝杯咖啡怎么样  -好啊
Where?
去哪儿喝